<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title type="main">Treasure Island [Electronic resource] / Robert Louis Stevenson</title>
        <author>Stevenson, Robert Louis, 1850-1894</author>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <name>University of Oxford Text Archive</name>
          <address>
                  <addrLine>Oxford University Computing Services</addrLine>
                  <addrLine>13 Banbury Road</addrLine>
                  <addrLine>Oxford</addrLine>
                  <addrLine>OX2 6NN</addrLine>
               </address>
          <email>ota@oucs.ox.ac.uk</email>
        </distributor>
        <idno type="ota">http://ota.ox.ac.uk/id/5730</idno>
        <availability status="restricted">
          <licence target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/"> Distributed by the
            University of Oxford under a Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported
            License </licence>
        </availability>
      </publicationStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <p>This text is a TEI version of a Project Gutenberg text originally located at <ptr
            target="http://www.gutenberg.org/dirs/1/2/0//120/"/>. As per their license agreement we
          have removed all references to the project's trademark, however have included this pointer
          to the original in case you want the plain text, or their XHTML version. </p>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <langUsage>
        <language ident="eng">English</language>
      </langUsage>
      <textClass>
        <keywords scheme="#OTASH">
          <term type="genre">Novels</term>
        </keywords>
        <keywords scheme="#LCSH">
          <term type="genre">Scottish literature -- 19th century</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
      <textClass>
        <keywords scheme="http://www.ota.ox.ac.uk/processing">
          <term type="class">text</term>
          <term type="license">CC BY-SA</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>
    <revisionDesc>
      <change when="2012-09-05T13:51:24.862+01:00"/>
    </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <front>
      <div>
        <head>TREASURE ISLAND</head>
        <quote>
          <p>To S.L.O., an American gentleman in accordance with whose classic taste the following
            narrative has been designed, it is now, in return for numerous delightful hours, and
            with the kindest wishes, dedicated by his affectionate friend, the author.</p>
        </quote>
      </div>
    </front>
    <body>
      <div>
        <head>PART ONE—The Old Buccaneer</head>
        <div type="div3">
          <head>The Old Sea-dog at the Admiral Benbow</head>
          <p>This is a fake paragraph containing the string United States because we want to show
            off. </p>
          <p>"Now, that bird," he would say, "is, maybe, two hundred years old, Hawkins—they live
            forever mostly; and if anybody's seen more wickedness, it must be the devil himself.
            She's sailed with England, the great Cap'n England, the pirate. She's been at
            Madagascar, and at Malabar, and Surinam, and Providence, and Portobello. She was at the
            fishing up of the wrecked plate ships. It's there she learned 'Pieces of eight,' and
            little wonder; three hundred and fifty thousand of 'em, Hawkins! She was at the boarding
            of the viceroy of the Indies out of Goa, she was; and to look at her you would think she
            was a babby. But you smelt powder—didn't you, cap'n?"</p>
          <p>"Stand by to go about," the parrot would scream.</p>
          <p>"Ah, she's a handsome craft, she is," the cook would say, and give her sugar from his
            pocket, and then the bird would peck at the bars and swear straight on, passing belief
            for wickedness. "There," John would add, "you can't touch pitch and not be mucked, lad.
            Here's this poor old innocent bird o' mine swearing blue fire, and none the wiser, you
            may lay to that. She would swear the same, in a manner of speaking, before chaplain."
            And John would touch his forelock with a solemn way he had that made me think he was the
            best of men.</p>
          <p>In the meantime, the squire and Captain Smollett were still on pretty distant terms
            with one another. The squire made no bones about the matter; he despised the captain.
            The captain, on his part, never spoke but when he was spoken to, and then sharp and
            short and dry, and not a word wasted. He owned, when driven into a corner, that he
            seemed to have been wrong about the crew, that some of them were as brisk as he wanted
            to see and all had behaved fairly well. As for the ship, he had taken a downright fancy
            to her. "She'll lie a point nearer the wind than a man has a right to expect of his own
            married wife, sir. But," he would add, "all I say is, we're not home again, and I don't
            like the cruise."</p>
        </div>
      </div>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
